<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Ankit Gubiligari</title>
    <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Ankit Gubiligari</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 6: Verizon Case Study to Reduce Customer Defaulting on Payments</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>● Led a thorough analysis of Verizon&amp;rsquo;s customer demographic data employing Python and Tableau, strategically tackling profitability challenges and devising preventative measures against future customer defaults on payment plans.
● Executed a comprehensive data cleansing, transformation, and analysis using Python and Tableau, systematically determining the significance of variables and pinpointing essential factors required for conclusive decision-making.
● Employed a random forest classification model to effectively address the issue of customer defaults, leveraging advanced statistical techniques to enhance predictive accuracy and refine decision-making processes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 5: Fitness Center Case Study to Reduce Customer Churn</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>● Utilized the scikit-learn package in Python to develop a logistic regression model, providing valuable predictive insights for the fitness center to effectively mitigate customer churn.
● Conducted preliminary data cleansing and exploratory data analysis (EDA) to identify key columns for analysis and determine the necessary data to formulate a comprehensive strategy for churn reduction.
● Proposed a final AGILE-based solution plan to follow in order to reduce churn by 10%.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: McDonald&#39;s Case Study on Promotions vs. Profit/Foot Traffic</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>● Spearheaded comprehensive analysis of McDonald&amp;rsquo;s food/customer data using Python/Tableau to address profitability challenges and declining foot traffic in franchisee establishments.
● Involved data integrity assessments, creation of insightful data visualizations, and development of a strategy to enhance profit margins by a targeted 10%.
● Implemented machine learning algorithms to identify key factors influencing customer preferences and behavior, providing actionable insights for menu optimization and marketing strategies.
Key Visualization/Insights:
Corporate Stores are generating more revenue than franchisee stores: All-Day Breakfast promotion release causes spike in breakfast items being sold with decrease in chicken items being sold: Promotion should be deployed within May, August, or November due to sales peaks during these months: Link to EDA: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Analysis of Movie Budget and Movie Characteristics on Gross Revenue</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>● Transformed data and conducted correlation testing on chosen dataset, leveraging python packages (pandas, numpy,matplotlib, seaborn).
● Performed data clean-up on dataset to ensure all variables were numerical in data type and removed null/duplicate values.
● Created visualization plots (scatterplot/heatmap) to evaluate relationship between budget and gross revenue. Performed 3 correlations tests, with specific emphasis on Pearson’s coefficient to assess relationship between variable pairs.
● Findings revealed substantial pearson’s coefficient of 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Analysis of Alcohol Consumption and % Health Expenditure on Life Expectancy</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>● Utilized various R packages (dplyr, ggplot2, corrplot, tidyverse, etc.) to conduct hypothesis testing with a selected dataset.
● Employed linear regression to construct 2 predictive models, analyzing impact of factors (alcohol consumption, health expenditure, etc.), on the average life expectancy across different countries (both developing and developed).
● Conducted statistical assessments to examine significance of scientific inquiries involving five+ potential predictors of interest/potential confounding variables. Findings revealed difference of approximately 7.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: COVID-19 Vaccination Trends in the U.S.A</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Guiding Questions for Analysis:
How did the population of COVID-19 vaccinated people change over time in 2021?
How did the number of total distributed vaccinations change in Washington State over time in January, 2021?
How does the total number of vaccinations distributed affect the number of vaccinated people in Washington in January, 2021?
Task Completed:
● Leveraged key R packages (ggplot2, dplyr, tidyverse) to comprehensively analyze the distribution rates of vaccinations across many different states within America.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 7: Analyzing Apple Stock Revenue Over the History of the Company:</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>● Used MSSQL to clean up/wrangle data for visualization in PowerBI, to assess the decline in Apple stock from 1900s to 2020.
Key Insights:
Apple Losing Revenue as the Years increase: Apple Stock Price is steadily flunctauating from 1999 2013: Link to PowerBI Dashboard: https://github.com/ankitgb/PortfolioProjects/blob/main/SQL%26PowerBIProject1.pdf
Link to SQL Queries:
https://github.com/ankitgb/PortfolioProjects/blob/main/SQLQuery1Project1.sql
https://github.com/ankitgb/PortfolioProjects/blob/main/SQLQuery2Project1.sql</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name is Ankit Gubiligari and I am based in Seattle, Washington. My enthusiasm lies in the realm of data science and analytics, spanning diverse sectors such as healthcare, marketing, and finance. As a final-year Graduate Student at the University of Chicago, I am actively engaged in pursuing a Masters of Science in Applied Data Science. My academic journey includes a prior graduation from the University of Washington Seattle with a degree in biochemistry and data science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/contact/</guid>
      <description>Here is my contact information:
Feel free to reach out! I&amp;rsquo;d love to connect and talk more about any my previous experiences or personal projects!
Platform Link: Email: Ankitgg@uchicago.edu Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ankit-gubiligari-4013a026b/ Github: https://github.com/ankitgb/PortfolioProjects Phone: 425-677-4269 </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
